ALEXIS SAN JAVIER

Lakeland, FL 33805 | Phone: 863-513-5577 | Email: alexissj16@knights.ucf.edu

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/alexissi | GitHub: www.github.com/code-guy21 | Portfolio: www.alexissi.com | Code-guy21 | Portfolio: www.alexissi.com

SUMMARY

Full stack web developer with a background in education and research. Recognized as a dynamic, creative, and motivated problem solver. An excellent communicator with outstanding leadership and teamwork qualities. A graduate of The University of Central Florida with a Bachelor's in Computer Engineering and a Certificate in Full Stack Web Development.

TECHNICAL SKILLS —

• Front End: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, jQuery

• Back End: Node, Express

• Database: MongoDB, MySQL

• Version Control: Git

PROJECTS

HomeBody – Github: github.com/code-guy21/Homebody | Deployed: homebody-fitness.herokuapp.com Web application that auto generates user workouts based on exercise preferences

- Worked on a team of four and was responsible for building Authentication flow, API, and Database
- Tech Stack: React, Node, Express, Mongoose, MongoDB, Passport, Cookie-Session

Droplet – Github: <u>github.com/code-guy21/droplet</u> | Deployed: <u>project-droplet.herokuapp.com</u> Social media web application that allows users to comment on and create text-based posts

- Led a team of four and was responsible for building API, Database, and Authentication flow
- Tech Stack: jQuery, HTML, CSS, Node, Express, MySQL, Sequelize

BookSearch – Github: github.com/code-guy21/BookSearch | Deployed: booksearchgo.herokuapp.com Web application that implements Google Books API and allow users to search for and save book titles

- Worked independently to build Front End, Database, and API
- Tech Stack: React, Node, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE -

TRILOGY - Remote

09/2020 - Present

Teaching Assistant & Tutor

 Responsible for assisting instructional team and providing technical/educational support to students as part of a full stack web development program

SYNAPSE - Orlando, FL

11/2016 - 09/2018

After School Coordinator

• Founding employee responsible for developing program structure, lesson plans, and projects for a roster of ~30 students as part of an after-school STEM curriculum.

- Coordinated program execution and provided engaging and in-depth lecture to students, resulting in positive reviews and enrollment growth
- Successfully planned and executed a robotics challenge as part of <u>The Modern Classroom's</u> educational tour, which led them to become repeat clients and partners.

THE UNIVERSITY OF CENTRAL FLORIDA – Orlando, FL

01/2017 - 05/2018

Research Assistant

- Collaborated with researchers and engineers to develop simulations, run experiments, and troubleshoot testing equipment to ensure consistent and accurate data collection.
- Successfully developed a virtual-reality brain simulation to test the memory and retention rates of medical students, using Unreal Engine and HTC Vive, as part of a study conducted by Dr. Grace Teo

EDUCATION —	
<u>Full Stack Web Development Certificate</u> – Orlando, FL The University of Central Florida	2020
Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering – Orlando, FL The University of Central Florida	2017